

# www.lizfaria.com



# efaria93@gmail.com



# @lizcookscode

# **ABOUT**

Hi, my name's Liz and I'm a full stack developer based in Toronto who specializes in JavaScript. I work hard because I want to be part of expanding possibilities and creating high quality online experiences. I love to collaborate across teams to solve problems and help build an outstanding product that has a positive impact on users' lives.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Ownr, April 2020 - Present

- develop on the core application to collect data and build automations using React, Node, Jest and Puppeteer
- build an email campaigns microservice using TypeScript, Node, SQL, Swagger-UI and PostgreSQL
- empower the CS team by adding RESTful GraphQL endpoints to update client data on the admin application
- help build the custom component library to match the Zeplin designs and migrate the frontend codebase to use ES6, React, React-Query, Styled Components, GraphQL, Web sockets, Node, and Jest
- write documentation and champion standards for WCAG accessibility
- buddy with new team members to walkthrough codebases, documentation, coding standards and Git practices

### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

TouchBistro, March 2019 - April 2020

- collaborate with an agile team to add new reporting features to improve customer's business insights and experience, as well as improve existing performance, data reliability and accessibility
- led the migration of the frontend codebase to a more maintainable and performant codebase using ES6, TypeScript, Node, React, React Context, and unit and integration testing JS frameworks

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Tennis Design, September 2018 - October 2019

- develop websites for major education, arts, science, technology and business organizations using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Django templating and Git
- stay informed with innovative web technologies, web design trends, and best practices in backwards compatibility, responsiveness and accessibility
- work with designers and a back-end developer to scope, refine and implement invision prototypes

#### **MENTOR**

Canada Learning Code & Juno School of Technology, April 2018 - March 2022

- engage with students, clarify class material, and mark projects for the Accelerated Web Development and JavaScript Courses at Juno College of Technology
- empower budding developers to feel a sense of belonging and excitement about tech and coding

# **EDUCATION**

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PT**

Bridge, Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 Advanced program focusing on ES6 React, Redux, Test-Driven development, Git Flow, Agile development and leadership skills.

## **WEB DEV BOOTCAMP**

HackerYou, Apr 2018 - June 2018 Intensive program with a focus on JavasScript, React, CSS, HTML, Pair Programming and Git skills through hands-on, project-based learning.

## **B.A. PHILOSOPHY + SOCIOLOGY**

University of King's College, Sept 2013 - May 2017

First class honours in Contemporary Studies and Sociology.